[SPEAKER_02]: A kid used to have me autographed, you know, on books like this.
[SPEAKER_02]: I looked at it and I'd say, what's up with that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Pictures, you know, he had this album.
[SPEAKER_02]: His wife and I got married.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd never seen a picture of the paper.
[SPEAKER_02]: This kid had it and I'd say, what do you want for this?
[SPEAKER_02]: So I bought the whole album book from him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I gave him $10 for it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't want nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he had so many write-ups and clip-ins in there that I didn't even know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where'd you borrow from?
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh, how did you...
[SPEAKER_02]: So he said, I'll start a new one.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you break into baseball in Danville, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Back in the 3-I-L-A, was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you, who scouted you?
[SPEAKER_01]: What about a name of Doc Bennett?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bennett, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: See Detroit Connection?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
No.
[SPEAKER_01]: White Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: And what, were you pitching Sandlot Ball there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Granville, was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I was in Columbus.
[SPEAKER_01]: Must have been doing pretty well.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you reported to Danville then, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he signed me to Danville.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you pretty excited about that, getting a chance to play professional ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did your parents think about it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were they interested, too, in your career, your parents?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know too much about baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tyler was a coal miner.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had his own trouble.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those days, you know, coal miners didn't make much money.
[SPEAKER_02]: For you, would you have gone in the coal mines if you hadn't been a...
[SPEAKER_02]: I did work.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's foreclosing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right, as a boy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that ever bother you, pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: My wife used to massage it, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Harder than, believe it or not, you know, Ripley, believe it or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_02]: Three-fingered brown and...
[SPEAKER_01]: According to this book, you had 12 and 16 with Danville.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Red Sox bought you right away, though, for $4,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you think about that, going up to the Red Sox there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I didn't mind it because it was a big league.
[SPEAKER_02]: They were in last place, though, weren't they?
[SPEAKER_02]: I roped up the season in the last place and stayed there all year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you didn't stay with them very long though, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I went from 24 to 30.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I meant that first year in 24 when they... No, they sent me down to a place called Dover.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dover, Delaware.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that a pretty good little lake there, the Eastern Shore Lake?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they had some big riggers there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had some foxes and a winged guitar.
[SPEAKER_01]: That year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you pitch against him?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you, uh...
[SPEAKER_02]: Pitch against him enough to own a big rig.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about, did you ever hear of Ben Johnson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Big rig president, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet him, or... No, I never did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never met him, huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm trying to write a book about Ben Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went to school where I teach, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm trying to write a book about him, and I can't find anybody who really knew him because, well, it was quite a while ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then players apparently didn't mingle with the president.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had no occasion to, unless you were called on the carpet, I guess, in the office there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Roger Peckinpah told me he got the
[SPEAKER_02]: He should know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, well, he got the most liable player award in 1925.
[SPEAKER_01]: He doesn't even remember Van Johnson giving it to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Although Van did give those to some of the players.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, who was managing Boston when you went up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Lee Fole.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he a pretty good manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he worked for what he had.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wasn't too much talent then, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Not really.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why was this?
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't have any money to buy?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, they didn't have any money.
[SPEAKER_02]: The bank wouldn't give them any money.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who owned the club?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bob Quinn.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Quinn was the farm director of the Cleveland Indians.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that his son?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, that's his grandfather.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I always thought Quinn was a very good baseball man.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gets the money to get the players, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the players on that team back in the 20s, or the Red Sox, if you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we had Bashay in left, Flagstead in center, Ike Broome in right field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ira Flagstead.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a pretty good ball player, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about any infielders that are very well-known?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oscar Malelo, is he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in the Browns, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in the Browns.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now that kid by the name of Dudley Lee is a very good shot, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dudley Lee, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about first base?
[SPEAKER_01]: Phil Tote.
[SPEAKER_01]: Danny McFadden, one of the pitchers?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he grew up later on.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was one of the first to wear glasses, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the toughest hitters you faced when you were in Boston?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you had the Yankees in Kentucky, wasn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Ruth to pitch to?
[SPEAKER_02]: Pretty rough.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any weaknesses?
[SPEAKER_01]: You got to keep the ball high.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you let it on, it hurts us.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sure enough, it'll feed to bleachers.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You ever in Yankee City?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know where the bullpen is, way down left there, where they warm up?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Baby, it went off me in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why the pokes were on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: In left field, you say?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, where they warm up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bullpen.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't think it was a high one.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a low drive, a line drive.
[SPEAKER_01]: That one must have been up.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Babe personally?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get to know him pretty well when he went over to the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've been over to his house several times.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a playboy, they say?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a playboy, but he was just a kid at heart.
[SPEAKER_02]: My old babe was quite a guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I liked him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Matter of fact, everybody liked him in the league.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did he call you, a kid?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess he didn't know their names, did he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't call Jake Rupert a kid, I hope.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he call him Jake?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how did you know about your trade to the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or did the manager call you in?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or would you read about in the paper?
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you first hear about your being traded to the Yankees in 1930?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that was a funny thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I knew I was going to be traded to somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because at that time, I think I lost five.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Five and all.
[SPEAKER_02]: I knew I was going to be traded because you know you hear rumbles.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I was dressing alongside this shortstop of ours, Al Ryan.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to be with the Pirates a long time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was dressing alongside of him, and Heine Wagener was the manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I seen the Western Union guy come out on the bench that day, give the manager a telegram or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was saying to the company guys, I said, boys, I'll be seeing you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just out of the acorn, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I gave him the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came up to me and shook my hand and said, well, so long.
[SPEAKER_02]: I hope you have success.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where are you going?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, where am I going?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I sent you to a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, to the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he didn't tell me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He went straight to me and said, I hope you have good success.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I ran outside and he says, where are you going?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I don't know, he didn't tell me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, god damn it, we'll find out.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I said, honey, where am I going?
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, to the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, oh my god.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't wait to get back to tell Ryan.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, when are you leaving?
[SPEAKER_02]: I told Ryan, he said, when are you leaving?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, a couple of days.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, a couple of days?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, if I stay with the Yankees, I'll be gone right now.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had lost five straight with Boston just before that trade.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you finished the season with 15 and 8.
[SPEAKER_01]: That must have turned right around then.
[SPEAKER_01]: They weren't leading the league, were they?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Philly, the A's were probably leading the league then, but the Yankees must have been right behind them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob Shockey, managing the Yankees here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was managing the Yankees, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: About the only year, I guess, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how'd they greet you when you get over to the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_01]: The players and the manager?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, they'd give me a howl.
[SPEAKER_02]: What the hell you doing here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Can't help us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you find that they
[SPEAKER_01]: really go after you or is this just a... Well, Bill Huggins was the manager of the club in 1925.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was at the front of the city office, you know how they do out there, the flies to the outfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was sitting on a bench and I was over on that side.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, hey, Ruffin.
[SPEAKER_02]: I turned around and he says, come here a minute.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went over.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I'm going to make it a habit of talking to the visiting ball players.
[SPEAKER_02]: At that time, I was playing the outfield, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I was playing the outfield a few games.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I guess he's going to try to make an outfield on me, because I get hit pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he called me over.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, what are they trying to do, make an outfield out of you?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I guess so.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I can't win ball games until I get to try something else.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, you just tell them you don't want to play the outfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, why?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you'll be over on this club next year.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you just tell them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know how the hell I'm going to tell this to Washington.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't want to bring it out to them, because you can't do it anyway.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because if they tell you to go, you've got to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: So Huggins had his eye on you before the Yankees got you.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the same year, he died.
[SPEAKER_02]: So when he died, I said, there goes my trade.
[SPEAKER_02]: There goes Ruffin from the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was all cut and dried, I guess, before he passed away.
[SPEAKER_02]: All he had was a pimple on his face and scratches.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that what it did?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess not.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of things really began to move up for you, didn't they?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had some good years.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1932 we won a pennant.
[SPEAKER_01]: We won a game in the World Series, yeah?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember that game you won?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it a close game?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I think it was 12-8.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Ruth's calling his shot that serious?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that was in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he really call that in the event, or what were the circumstances?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Charlie Rook, the pitcher, he said he didn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said it was a damn lie.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_02]: He pointed right out to center field bleachers after they had two strikes on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Next pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you remember Woody English?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he pretty tough?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember him as a hitter?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he wasn't bad, he wasn't bad either.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not the way they run them, the shortstops.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the toughest hitters you faced after you got over the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll tell you, they were all tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_01]: Good luck with them though, according to the record here.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Earl Abram?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: God, he's hitting that band box now, and there's only 250 feet to the right of the wall.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that a tough part to pitch in, would you say?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You thinking about that wall when you're pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Try to keep it away from those guys, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was in one of those areas one day, and well, we were in together most of the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was in the Cleveland Hotel.
[SPEAKER_02]: He went downstairs, and when he came back up, I was sitting in the clothes closet, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, what the hell are you doing there sitting in the clothes closet?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I got a pitch today, so when I go out that damn band box, I look like the Yankee Stadium team.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got such a kick out of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that a pretty happy team, those Yankees?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jokes and good relations?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Joe McCarthy?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was all right if he wasn't drinking.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_01]: What did Shockey go for?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, Shockey was just there about a year, I guess, wasn't he, or two, and then McCarthy came in, and I wondered what Shockey... wasn't he a good manager or...
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess not.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why I let him go, because he brought Joe McArthur over next year, and next year he won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess if you win, that makes you a good manager, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've got to win a pennant to be a manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you win a pennant, it seems like you always get a job.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think managing is that important for you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: It seems like if you have good material, you're going to win, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Casey Stengel, he couldn't do much with the Boston Braves, but the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1933, you had a kind of a bad year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a bad arm that year or something?
[SPEAKER_01]: 1914, I'd say.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, the last year I had a bad shoulder.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then you came back real well in 1934.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Lou Gehrig?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a good hard-nosed player.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gehrig's more of a serious type than very ruthless.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob Musil, a pretty...
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a good officer.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a terrific one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ordinary five balls you see now, left fielders get eyes on the turn, calling home.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wouldn't do that on Musial.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd throw you out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Ruth would too, wouldn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Ruth would do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would sum it up for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Earl Combs?
[SPEAKER_01]: He had pretty good arms?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: In fact, Combs has a stroke too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Can't use his arms.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hope to get down to see him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He doesn't live too far from where we are, in Kentucky there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he's in, what's his name?
[SPEAKER_02]: Richmond.
[SPEAKER_01]: Richmond, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we were at a meeting last spring up in Monterey on a... Somebody read a paper on Babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_01]: A fellow had written a paper on him, and he had interviewed Earl Combs once or twice.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think this was before he had his stroke, but he had a nice visit down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of your other picks?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Lefty Gomez as a teammate and pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lefty and I roomed together.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he pretty much of a prankster and pulling jokes all the time?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he didn't really love that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not too much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he as witty, as humorous as they said?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Keeps everybody loosened up, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was quite a kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever get thrown out of any games?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tried to, but the umpires wouldn't throw me out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why'd you try to?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was definitely between lefty and I. Lefty used to pitch, and I managed to let him off the next day.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he'd take his wife to the beach.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I went to MacArthur one day, I says,
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I'm married, I could use a damn day off, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, we need you for pinch hitting.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no, it's a lot of crap, Joe.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, no, it isn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you're a team man, aren't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I decided my only way I'm going to get a day off is I'm going to Sunday a close play.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm going to get on the umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: Make him throw me out of the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: So what happened one day on a close play at third base, I started riding the umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, I know you're kidding me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I'm not kidding you.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're blind, so-and-so.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, referee, if you think I'm going to throw you out of the game so you can go to the beach, you're crazy.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've got to stay here and suffer with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, thanks so much.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: When did you get married?
[SPEAKER_02]: When?
[SPEAKER_02]: 1934.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you meet your wife through some of the baseball connections?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, just my hometown.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do in the winter times?
[SPEAKER_01]: Nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go back home and go hunting?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I used to do a little hunting, but not much.
[SPEAKER_02]: too hard on my foot, I couldn't walk through those rough terrain, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mean where you lost the toes?
[SPEAKER_01]: How did that affect your pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that where you put the weight on the foot there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I put it on the side.
[SPEAKER_02]: Land on my side and then flop over on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I hit like that, and then came like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very special shoot, let's say.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't bother hitting your pitching, did it?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many home runs did you hit in your career, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what's wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's something I say, I didn't know how many home runs I hit or anything.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was sitting and talking one day, and we had a statistician there from, what, the ball club of Cleveland years ago?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he was a shootie.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was terrific.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know all about him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: I forget his name, but he hung himself.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said he had a brain.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, that's what happens.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he's too bright.
[SPEAKER_02]: Too bright.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hung himself the first time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He talked to me one day, he says, do you know you have a record in who's who after being the best hitting pitcher in baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no, I don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you hit over 300 seven years in a row in a pitcher?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, what's in who's who?
[SPEAKER_02]: I never knew it, but he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you wanted to know these things when it came contract time, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: It didn't help.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever hold out any?
[SPEAKER_01]: Every year.
[SPEAKER_01]: For how long?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, one time I held out till May.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was the Yankees, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who'd you negotiate your contracts with?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ed Barrow?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ed Barrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was he to deal with?
[SPEAKER_01]: Tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I bet he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Would you each give in a little bit then before you finally signed?
[SPEAKER_02]: We'd have to trust each other out over the phone sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did it take you long to get in shape in the spring when you held out like that, or did you keep in shape?
[SPEAKER_02]: I kept in shape, yeah, I lived in California at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm out there to play ball all year round.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's always somebody working on it, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: It really wasn't a problem getting in shape.
[SPEAKER_02]: Actually, I lived in Long Beach and had a ballpark down there, and every Sunday they played ball games there, so I used to be out every Sunday and work out.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I got my arm in pretty good shape, I pitched about four or five innings.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I got to spring training, I was ready.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was embarrassed with that as well as anybody else because they had their scouts out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They watched every ball game.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't tell them New York, you know, they'd call up, say Ruffin's working out of his pitch and he's in pretty good shape.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they never worried about me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm out of hell out.
[SPEAKER_02]: They figured I'd be ready to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: I remember you had it so hard.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was out playing golf.
[SPEAKER_02]: The heavy Yankees carried out California.
[SPEAKER_02]: He walked around the whole 18 holes with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't want my arm, kept asking about my arm and that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did I feel good and all that stuff?
[SPEAKER_02]: I know what he's up to.
[SPEAKER_02]: If I'd have said, yo, my arm's still hurting, I'd have been treated.
[SPEAKER_02]: Next day.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know they checked up on them that way.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sneaky.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sneaky way of doing it, but they do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But did you move to California then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or were you just spending some time there?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, when I got married, my wife and I went out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had been living in Illinois all these years?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you live near Jim Bottomley and all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Jim and I from the same town.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he was from Illinois.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sonny Jim, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I've been working on him to get him in the Hall of Fame for years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he succeeded.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's something.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little town like that with two Hall of Famers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it's only 1,200 people in it.
[SPEAKER_02]: The street had a lot of room there.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had these cow fields, and they used to make ball downs out of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd all put bases down and go over there and play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you and he play as kids or about the same age?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jimmy owned up before I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Matter of fact, that's the only time we got to know each other, when he's in a big loose house.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever pitch against him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they'd get rings all the time, no other days at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never a regular one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Joe DiMaggio came up.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Joe?
[SPEAKER_01]: 1936.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nice boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a ball player of the day.
[SPEAKER_02]: He stepped in camp.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could do it all, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: You do.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he a pretty good team player?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Ruth when Ruth left the team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there some kind of decline in spirit, do you think?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was pretty well through then, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he's all washed out.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, talking with so many of these, the ones I go along on for the ride, these old ballplayers, it seems to me, of course this is just my view, I don't know anything, that the players today don't seem to have nearly the same attitude or team spirit that they used to.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd probably get $250,000 a year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd probably get $24,000 a year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that your top figure in the late 30s there?
[SPEAKER_02]: You started winning 21, 20 games over a year.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many 20-game years did you have?
[SPEAKER_01]: Four.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your best pitch?
[SPEAKER_01]: Pass ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pass ball, I mixed it up with a change of pace.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a picture of you in this book here.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is the 39th edition.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had 21 and 7, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: You struck out about 120 strikeouts a year or so, and you averaged about 70 or so walks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty good ratio, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, which a lot of them are, you know, intentionally.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you pitched over, boy, you went over 250 inning zones every year there for many years.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a lot of innings.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you ever pitch 300 innings a season?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wouldn't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, in our day, they didn't know what they were doing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Today, everything you do is a record.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get a hangnail.
[SPEAKER_02]: You went to the clubhouse and got it cut off.
[SPEAKER_02]: It had to be in the paper.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get a picture and everything in the paper.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's not a hangnail.
[SPEAKER_02]: If I saw him, I'd have paid for it myself.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd have to fix it.
[SPEAKER_02]: They get up.
[SPEAKER_02]: They take care of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I remember I was going to a World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: We played Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: That year, I beat Paul Garrett at 2-1.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I couldn't move my arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: I couldn't move my shoulder.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I told McCarthy, I said, I can't open it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, why not?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I got a sore shoulder.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, oh, for Christ's sake.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't get a word, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: He calls in a head scout from New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you know any doctor around here that knows anything about arms?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, yeah, I know a guy in Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, he wants $25 for treatment.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, get him over here.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I got to work, though.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm going to have to pay for it myself.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's kind of a club thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hey, you think they'd get away with that today?
[SPEAKER_01]: Never.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he fix your arm or loosen it up a little?
[SPEAKER_02]: He loosened it up.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got it loose pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you went out and pitched, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched a big game, two to one.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I went up to the front office and I said, how about my money for my arm?
[SPEAKER_02]: Boy, you saved your own arm by doing that.
[SPEAKER_02]: We don't pay for that, Bearer says.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that Bearer?
[SPEAKER_02]: Boy, he was tough.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wouldn't give his mother a dollar, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now they pay for everything, operations, hospitalization.
[SPEAKER_01]: All the fringe benefits.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they just fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it shows in the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think that's why interest is falling off in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: They didn't go out there, they don't put their soul into it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It seemed like the older players, this was their life.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some of these younger players, it's a stepping stone to something else.
[SPEAKER_01]: They just don't have the luck of the game, apparently.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you know, they asked me one time, what's the difference of pitching today and in your day?
[SPEAKER_02]: I says, a lot of difference.
[SPEAKER_02]: How do you think?
[SPEAKER_02]: So that's how I figured.
[SPEAKER_02]: Today, you go out there and pitch a pretty good ballgame.
[SPEAKER_02]: I tell the writer, well, I thought I pitched pretty good today.
[SPEAKER_02]: And on the other day, I said, we had a win.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't say we thought we pitched a good game.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't get paid for that.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got paid to win.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we had a win.
[SPEAKER_02]: One night, I said, oh, I thought I did pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Either you win or you don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they get saved today.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, saves.
[SPEAKER_01]: They count up as much as victories.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just for a kickoff game, saves.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he may have a record of two wins and three defeats, but he's got 12 saves.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a great year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mike Marshall and all his saves.
[SPEAKER_01]: How often did they, when you went out to pitch, you were supposed to pitch a whole game, weren't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't tell you to go out and pitch five good innings.
[SPEAKER_01]: But now they have these long relievers and short relievers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get reliever?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they knock you out much?
[SPEAKER_01]: Not much, not much.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd do it all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, you were different.
[SPEAKER_01]: You could hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could hit and it wouldn't take long.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd keep you in the game more because of that.
[SPEAKER_02]: What do you think of the designator-hitter idea?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd have a good time in this day and age, wouldn't I?
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd still be...
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Yankee Stadium to pitch in?
[SPEAKER_02]: Good.
[SPEAKER_02]: All along?
[SPEAKER_02]: Kept them up there and let them have it tomorrow, Joe.
[SPEAKER_02]: See them go up over their heads and say, go get it, Joe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any favorite ballparks?
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe that was it.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could run in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Seemed like Detroit to me, but I could beat anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you killed Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, I used to go down there and see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw my grub out there and see my Cleveland beat.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I didn't like you in those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was a Cleveland fan.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just killing all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you say some of their hitters gave you trouble, like Averill.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Trosky?
[SPEAKER_01]: Eat?
[SPEAKER_01]: Al Trosky.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't even know Trosky.
[SPEAKER_02]: As Jeff Heath said one time, I was interviewed on a ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was the World Series, in 1954 here.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came back from the coast.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jeff, the guy who was interviewing me, about pitching.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jeff overheard him and he was walking by.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, that son of a gun wouldn't give his mother a good ball of head.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, come on, Jeff, I gave you a lot of good work to hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, yeah, what the hell are you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you with the team then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you coaching them in the 54?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was in charge of personnel.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you come back to, how did you get on the Cleveland organization?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Hank Greenberg come here, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he and Ralph Conner were pretty good friends.
[SPEAKER_02]: I knew Ralph Conner.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ralph says, how would you like to work for Anne Greenberg?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I don't care.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I never thought no more of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: One day I got a call from Greenberg.
[SPEAKER_02]: Said, it's Anne Greenberg, and I'd like to work for her.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, OK.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I made a date on the beach.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you living in Florida then?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where were you making your regular home?
[SPEAKER_01]: California.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's when you came here.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's how we wound up here.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was like Cleveland anyway.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a beautiful city, you know, this time of year in the summer.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your last year in professional ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was at
[SPEAKER_01]: White Sox, 1947.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you in service in World War II?
[SPEAKER_01]: So you missed some years there, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Two and a half.
[SPEAKER_01]: Think you might have won 300 games?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I used to.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think so.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a shame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your father missed over almost four years, I guess, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He stayed up for a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what was your biggest thrill in baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Every day was a big thrill.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Used to play well, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Kids ask you that, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I get so many autographs.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just signed off about 30 the other day.
[SPEAKER_02]: They always want to know, what's your biggest thrill?
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, if I had the time, I'd feel good that day.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd rather know what you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: So my biggest thrill was signing you up.
[SPEAKER_02]: professional contract, getting the professional ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was being signed to the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_02]: After that, being signed to the New York Yankees and being in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's great.
[SPEAKER_02]: Topped a lot of bottles of cigarettes and with drugs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_02]: God, nowadays, they worry about you taking a drink.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they'd worry about you taking drugs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there a lot of drinking among ballplayers?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Big good drink of course, hot chocolate.
[SPEAKER_01]: And after a game or in the evening, you know?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And would he be ready the next day?
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd be ready.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never bothered.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never seen a guy with a hangover yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: How would the management handle that situation?
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Couldn't do nothing about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a big group.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: As long as he could produce, I guess they couldn't say much.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, one time, Lazari and I, we never went down for breakfast.
[SPEAKER_02]: Always had our breakfast thrown up in the room.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some rookie.
[SPEAKER_02]: He always had breakfast in the room and, uh, managed it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Charles, pardon me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pick up the phone and say hello to your sister.
[SPEAKER_00]: She tried to put everything out of my reach and all, make me work.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know,
[SPEAKER_00]: I know because my mother, I'm telling you why, my mother was in Highland View.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she was so frustrated anyway, because she was real active, I suppose the way you were.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when Nan, oh she would get so mad, and my dad would have everything just a little bit farther, and when she would make it that farther, she'd move a little bit farther away.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, that must have been their whole philosophy in Highland View.
[SPEAKER_02]: She had a stroke?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, she had a, in fact, she had about 12 of them within three years.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is my second in three years.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a stroke and I had two heart attacks after that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then after I got over the heart attacks, I had a kidney infection.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had to get an operation off the kidneys.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, they do that now today.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't touch you up anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: They use tubes.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was his story about you and Lazari had breakfast and Ms. Brook eat?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, we used to have our breakfast every morning in the room.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not our dinners, but our breakfast.
[SPEAKER_02]: Too lazy to go downstairs, and I didn't want to get dressed.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, you know, when Walter left town, the hotel would send all the bills to New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: You could see who was eating downstairs, who was eating in the room.
[SPEAKER_02]: So this kid, you know, Ms. Brook,
[SPEAKER_02]: He had breakfast in the room, and Carthy challenged him on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, how come you think we usually have breakfast in the room?
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, well, what's so bad about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, well, what's so bad about it?
[SPEAKER_02]: You're just a rookie.
[SPEAKER_02]: Get down and have your breakfast and let the rest of them do it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, Rafael Nazari doesn't have breakfast on every morning.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, let me tell you something.
[SPEAKER_02]: These are two established ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're not established yet.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't make the club yet.
[SPEAKER_02]: So this kid was telling us about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, well, let me give you some good advice, son.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, was there a, he was an epileptic?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he have any attacks that he had?
[SPEAKER_02]: He had one when I was there, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a fellow one morning there and he was out of bed just laying on the floor, you know, jumping around and shaking.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got scared as hell.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what the hell to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: I run out of room in my pajamas for help.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't know he had this.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't tell him about it, how it affected him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never had an attack on the field, I guess, did he?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Jake Powell?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you a teammate of his with the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was with us for a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had some attacks, I guess, with his bad nerve, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, I think I saw him when he was walking having an attack on the field.
[SPEAKER_01]: They carried him out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got in a lot of trouble.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yankees?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: Interviewed him one time and put him in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: The guy asked him, what do you do in the wintertime?
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, oh, I play cop during the winter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, get out on Akron.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, and hit these niggers over the head with clubs.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I guess they heard about this, all the colored people.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, they come up there pretty strong on us.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we went to Chicago from here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Boy, it is right out there, all those colored people.
[SPEAKER_01]: We need to give them hell.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever play against any black players at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: Barnstorming?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't do much barnstorming.
[SPEAKER_01]: Only once or twice.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not too much money involved, I'll tell you that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how about, what was, well, Frankie Cresetti, I guess, played short most of the time, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: I came in from Mizzou.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you still with him when Mizzou came in?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jerry Pretty.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got us in trouble, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: My crusaders used to drive me crazy.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd give me some runs, you know, and very seldom.
[SPEAKER_02]: They didn't ever like to make any runs for me.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd rather send me a pitch to one or nothing game or two to one than they would give me another run because I started experimenting, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: And just so they made a lot of runs, the crusaders would get mad, go all the way out there,
[SPEAKER_02]: and go up to the show stop and yell, OK, Ruffin, go ahead, Edison, go ahead, Thomas Edison, show us what you got, man.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I'd start laughing, you know, and I'd start fooling around with slow curves and all that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd say, there you go, that's a boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd be no good SB.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd say, I don't want to get married this fall.
[SPEAKER_02]: I need the extra money.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then when he got married, he had a kid, and then I had all I heard about the kid.
[SPEAKER_02]: When he had a 2-1 game, he knew he didn't have to worry about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you know what, bear down.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I just started making a lot of runs, and he started mowing out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You really experimented, I would assume.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I got a lot of runs, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did McCarty think about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't like it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He couldn't do nothing about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, he...
[SPEAKER_02]: I went back to Yankee's old timer's day one time, and Mrs. MacArthur was there, and she called me over.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, Red, can I see you a minute?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, I got something I want to tell you.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, I couldn't tell you when you was pitching.
[SPEAKER_02]: And she said, I just wanted to see you.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Mrs. MacArthur was there, and she called me over.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, Red, can I see you a minute?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I got something I want to tell you.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, I couldn't tell you when you was pitching.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, I can tell you now.
[SPEAKER_02]: She says, you know one thing?
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe McCarty, my husband, never slept good until you was pitching the next day.
[SPEAKER_02]: But when you was pitching that day, he said, that's the only time he relaxed.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's just nice to hear.
[SPEAKER_02]: She told me that.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, the only time he relaxed.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went down to Spring County one day, and I got to Spring County.
[SPEAKER_02]: I used to run a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I used to run.
[SPEAKER_02]: Keep my legs in shape.
[SPEAKER_02]: And one kid came over to McCarthy, and he smiled at the paper.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw it somewhere.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw the paper, the sporting news.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kid comes to McCarthy and says, what do I do when I'm in Spring County?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, see that guy out there?
[SPEAKER_02]: He meant me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you follow what he does, and you'll be in shape.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, dude, he does.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, yeah, everything he does, you do.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't see anything in anybody following, but I...
[SPEAKER_02]: I was a great believer in running.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were the Yankees a pretty good bench jockeying team?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the better ones?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Goldman's.
[SPEAKER_02]: I only got on people I've never seen.
[SPEAKER_02]: Like Roger Kramer or Ted Williams.
[SPEAKER_02]: The guys, you know, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You talk to them before the game, you know, or something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you know pretty well.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or Al Simmons.
[SPEAKER_02]: Once in a while, you know, once in a while you go to a bar or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think someone there from a different ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: I sat down and chatted with him and had a drink with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: It didn't mean nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd still go out there and try to win against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Al Simmons to pitch against?
[SPEAKER_01]: That foot in the bucket?
[SPEAKER_01]: How did he ever get his bat over the plate?
[SPEAKER_02]: His foot was in the bucket, but this wasn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: He seemed to violate all the rules of hitting.
[SPEAKER_01]: He put that foot in the bucket.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he was ready to hit, he'd chew his hips around the sand and bang to the pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you pitch to him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Try to pitch him tight.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you get one there, put your guts in him and throw it off him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd try to chew overhand, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's my best pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: a sidearm inside, and you had to throw down a few bleachers.
[SPEAKER_02]: So it was on a Sunday, and on a Sunday you couldn't get nothing to drink in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had the old German clubs there, you know, German clubs?
[SPEAKER_02]: You could get a drink at a German club, but they knew you, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So I thought, well, I'll get in the cab and go down there, and who was in there was Al Simmons.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I called him over, he said, come on, sit down with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he talks about that pitch I told him, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, don't throw that to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, don't throw that to nobody.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, your best picture's your grandpicture.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, stay with it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you throw that sidearm picture, there's nothing on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, if you want to keep throwing it to me, throw it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I don't care.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, don't do it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know the fellow helped you, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the way he helped me.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I try to tell these young kids that today.
[SPEAKER_02]: They look at you as if you're silly, you know, you're crazy.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I say,
[SPEAKER_02]: Each pitcher of our days, we helped each other.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, we'd talk to another pitcher on the club.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, if I could get Williams out, which I couldn't, but if I could, there'd be some pitcher come up to me and say, how do you pitch Williams?
[SPEAKER_02]: We can't get him out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd say, well, I pitch this way.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I'd say, turn around, if he had somebody on his club, or somebody I couldn't get out on some other club, I'd say, how do you pitch this home side?
[SPEAKER_02]: They really help you, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we help each other, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just talked to one of these kids today.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looked at us and said, you're nuts.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, because he was a boy at the college.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he say he didn't get much help?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, in the Pittsburgh organization.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, today they don't give much help.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did anybody help you when you went up to the Red Sox first?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't have many people that could help you, did you think?
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't have nobody behind.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were they?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember their pictures at that time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, there was myself, Ed Morris.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Ed Morris.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tony Welzer, Dale Longwood, Leonard Faden, Morris.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they didn't win many games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Morris, I guess, was pretty good, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some guy killed him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Down in the south, home town, four hours away, his wife stabbed him to death.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a fellow in Boston named Skerritt?
[SPEAKER_01]: Outfielder?
[SPEAKER_01]: Russ Skerritt?
[SPEAKER_01]: Russ Skerritt, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't kill him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, wow.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he any good?
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't have a good year?
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't too good either.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was just beginning to follow baseball then, seeing how many
[SPEAKER_01]: That name attracted me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never heard much more about him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was Regan?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember Regan?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a second baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm a third baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, that's a damn minute.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pitching was so bad, I almost got him killed.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Gaston with Boston then?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, Gaston.
[SPEAKER_01]: My brother Alec was a catcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't win many games, but we traveled first class, same as Wesley.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it like Fenway Park?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't mind it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get used to pitching now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't suppose you ever pitched an old Baker ball in Philadelphia, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess they really had that short right field one.
[SPEAKER_01]: To a truck line at 275.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then he went to Chicago and didn't do quite so well.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got surrounded.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember any really funny
[SPEAKER_01]: things happening on a ball field?
[SPEAKER_01]: Crazy plays or unusual plays that stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I remember one.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was a guy pitching for Washington this day, and he had the bases loaded.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pretty good hitter up there, and I never threw court balls, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Dickie came out and talked to me, and what we're going to do, how we're going to pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Missouri comes up from second base.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, really, how you going to do it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what the hell I'm going to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I'm going to throw the ball by him, I guess, and get him the hell out of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I'll throw him a curve ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He hit it to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I'll throw it home.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I think they can throw it the first thing I double play it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He did it.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what happened.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now we go to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_02]: Same situation.
[SPEAKER_02]: The bases loaded.
[SPEAKER_02]: Missouri comes running in.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, am I supposed to pitch this game for you again?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, well, do the same thing you did over at the Washington.
[SPEAKER_02]: Two of the guys curveballed, but I got a high.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, hit the goddamn thing way down on Centerfield Beach.
[SPEAKER_02]: I walked around with Missouri.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, don't even look at me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, pitch your own goddamn game.
[SPEAKER_01]: but I had jokes to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was pretty smart, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's smart.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's pretty shrewd, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: I heard a story Dr. Gomez told about him.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a run-down?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was some kind of a double play situation.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, a run-down play.
[SPEAKER_01]: And was there, he didn't cover the base at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: He walked up and gave him the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, what the hell did you hand me the ball for?
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, I read so much about you being a smart ball player, you should see what you're going to do with it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that was dark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that really happen?
[SPEAKER_00]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_02]: You mean he did?
[SPEAKER_01]: You wonder what some of this does.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Dickey, he's a pretty good catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: handle the game pretty well?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, well Dickie didn't really have no say.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't have a say.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not the last three or four years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how'd you operate then?
[SPEAKER_01]: He just took for a fastball on me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Except the Missouri Toys, that's all I care about.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you knew each other so well.
[SPEAKER_01]: You must have thrown some curve or change-ups or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I threw a change-up.
[SPEAKER_02]: But you couldn't cross him up like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, we crossed the catcher up when he was looking for a curveball and he threw a fastball.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, he said, if you're down there looking for a curveball, you're going to break the down low.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's when he threw a fastball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He can't get up there in time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's when he crossed the catcher's cross, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: But did you talk, did you have many meetings on the mound, you know, and plant like this one you mentioned with Ozeri?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you do that very often?
[SPEAKER_02]: And what did you talk about if you did?
[SPEAKER_02]: Just in Yankee Stadium, if you see, you know, the runways right facing you, you know, and you see a lot of movie stars from in there or somebody you knew, and you call Dickie out and say, hey Dickie, it's also just too much.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess people in the stand thought we were all talking business.
[SPEAKER_01]: You hear announcers sometimes say what they're talking about, what they'll eat for supper, where they're going to supper, and things like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you wonder if they really do or what they are talking about.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did you hear you were elected to the Hall of Fame?
[SPEAKER_01]: Where were you then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you here?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was here.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you hear about it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, my wife and I was out driving that day, wasn't we?
[SPEAKER_00]: You took me to lunch from work.
[SPEAKER_02]: I took you to lunch.
[SPEAKER_02]: As I drove up the street here, I saw all these TV trucks here and everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's how we got the first inkling.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had a big house, so we had cameras coming all over us.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball here, can you autograph it for me?
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't have any spare pictures around, do you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever have many pictures or scrapbooks?
[SPEAKER_02]: Like I said, I get most of the kids some.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kids send pictures to get autographed and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how you people ever were able to autograph baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you were right-handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: What his big problem was, it was her right side that went and she was right-handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me get that pen started for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: She looks good now.